Every 10 seconds, a star explodes
somewhere in the universe, blasting out
particles like this guy, the most
elusive particle in all of physics. And
for the next billion years, it just goes
straight because it's so small that it
can go through stars and planets and
walls and even you without hitting
anything. But this one, one day it flies
all the way through the Earth and then
just by chance it happens to run into a
proton inside a water molecule right
here off the coast of Sicily where
they've built a giant machine. And when
it hits the proton, it changes into a
heavier particle which flies through the
water faster than light can go in water
which makes basically a sonic boom of
light which these special sensors can
detect. And a computer on shore can
trace back where that elusive particle
actually came from, helping us find and
look inside some of the most important
events in our universe. to see what they
found. Subscribe.